Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- National Research Council Test at Hawthorne (1924-1927). Supplements information already at Cornell including information on illumination tests, original output charts prepared by Charles E. Snow (principle investigator at Hawthorne, 1924- 1927). Cove (Box 3)
  - Research at the Harvard Business School (article on Mayo p. 61), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Mayo Data 1922 (on Mayo coming to U.S.) (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Mayo to Pennock - April 29, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Mayo to Henderson (no date just "May 27") (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Western Electric Material in Mayo Files at Harvard, 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Articles in Newspapers on Elton Mayo, 1924-1946 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Letter from Melvin Copeland 10/21/58 on Mayo, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Elton Mayo and Colorado Fuel & Iron Co 1928-1930, Mayo 1980 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Emily Osborne Letter to Continental Mills on Pulse Product (1928) from Harvard (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Emily Osborne Letter to Wallace Donham on Mayo 6/14/28, Hawthorne, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Copies of original
  - Mayo - Harvard Records, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - William Lloyd Warner Correspondence on Mayo with William E. Duffy 1967 (Lloyd Warner 1967 Hawthorne) (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence on Mayo Papers at Harvard 1958 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Notes Taken at Harvard Business School April 4, 1958 - When Surveyed Hawthorne Files of Elton Mayo - On Continental Mills, Phila. 1925, 1926, 1928, 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Marge Eager's 1967 Study of Management and the Worker (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Grace Donavan Data (Mrs. Mound - England) Hawthorne 1964 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Mayo to Henderson (No date - just July 7th) 2 pp. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence with Clark Elliot - on Mayo & Peckham 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Copy of Letter from Peter Drucker (2/1/85) on Elton Mayo, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Elton Mayo to George Pennock - 1931 (copies) Hawthorne, Mayo 1931 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Pennock Letter to Mayo on "Special Interviews" 2/2/1931 (2 pages), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Will of Alfred Kroeber (Friend of Elton Mayo) 1960 (Mayo) 1979 Data, 1960-1979 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Data on Elton Mayo and University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Mayo in Philadelphia (1923) and Rest Pauses (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Elton Mayo, Report to Joseph Willits, 12/28/23 (ozalid copy, green, pp. 16-23 only, on Continental Mills) Filed in Elton Mayo File at Harvard, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - "The Hawthorne Studies in The Literature" Fortune, November 1946 "The Fruitful Errors of Elton Mayo" (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Data on Mayo and Illumination Tests From: Time, April 14, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Elton Mayo's Account of Work at Continental Mills, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Elton Mayo's Notes on Relay Assembly Test Room 1928 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Mayo to Pennock - 2/9/31, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Thermo fax Copies of Mayo Correspondence, 1922-1946 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Proceedings of First Annual Meeting on the 250 Associates of Harvard, Dec 6, 1930, Cambridge, Barta Press 1931 (section #2 on Mayo Research) (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Elton Mayo to Dr. Herman Feldman Social Science Research Council 3/30/28, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Mayo Letters 1928, 1929, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Elton Mayo Letters to Joseph Willits - Mayo, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Elton Mayo, The Social Problems of an Industrial Civilization (1945), p. 71 - Compared with W.E. Progress Reports (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Mayo and Stevenson Letters, 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rockefeller Archives - Copies of Mayo Letters 1927, 1925, 1925-1978 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    Three folders with copies and original documents
  - Search for Mayo Material in Rockefeller Archives 1983, 1930-1983 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Harvard University Research in Industrial Hazards - (Mayo & Henderson) 1929-1935 - From Rockefeller Foundation Archives - R 61.1, Ser. 200, Box 342, Folder 4070 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Rockefeller Archives & Mayo, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Photocopies of Elton Mayo Letters at Rockefeller Archives - Mayo, 1923-1931 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Mayo Letters at Rockefeller Archives, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Copy of a Portion of a Book on the Rockefeller Foundation from Greenwood 1982 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Copy of book
  - Mayo and 1930 Budget from Harvard, 1930-1957 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Mayo Material Rockefeller Archives 1927 Letters (Box 3, Folder 94)
- Correspondence with People Associated with Hawthorne. Duplicates and material related to National Research Council Material. Several sets of files led to duplicates for collocation purposes.. (Box 4)
  - Civil War History & NCH (NY Times, Nov. 6, 1960) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Original document (in sections pasted on paper)
  - Hawthorne Tests 1924-1932 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Copies of originals and transparency sheet
  - Correspondence on Hawthorne Dissertation with Agnew, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Austin Co. (on Illumination 9/17/58), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Donald Chipman Letters 1957 & 1964 - C Chipman Haw (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Ernest Dale on Selection on Hawthorne for Book of MST Readings 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Transcript of 1963 Landsberger Tape For Dale Book of Readings 1963, 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Augustus Kelley 1963 - On Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Ernest Dale 1963 (on Hawthorne) - Dale (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - D.D. Davidson (observer at Hawthorne 1932), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Douglas D. Davidson - Test from 47 Summit Road, Verona, NJ 07044 - Observations in Test Room 1932 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with University of Washington on William J. Dickson March 1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1956 Letter of W.J. Dickson on Illumination Tests June 13, 1956 and Max Howarth, 1956-1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - William J. Dickson to Herbert Borenstein 14 Ridge Rd. Parsippany, NJ - 1967 on Progress Reports (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Original and copy
  - William J. Dickson Personal File 7/1/1929 (Hawthorne) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Original and copy of document
  - William Dickson Letter to Homer Hibarger on Original Tests at Hawthorne June 20, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - William Fox Correspondence on Hawthorne 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Copy of "Memorandum of Record - Illumination Experiments" Issued by W.J. Dickson, June 18, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Roethlisberger Letters to Dickson, 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Robert Gale - Assoc. of Edison Illuminatory Companies 12/30/58 on seeing Illuminate of Association, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Search for William Drugin Illumination Experiments (1918) 1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Larry Glick W. E. Training Program 1962 W.E. Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Paper for Western Electric Training Program on Hawthorne Studies by C.D. Wrege, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Summary of Relay Assembly Test Room Results (Prepared for W.E. Mgt Training Program, 1962), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Brief Account of The Origins of The Hawthorne Studies - by C.D. Wrege - July 20, 1965 for Western Electric Training Program (13 pages) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - C.D. Wrege, Brief Account of Hawthorne Studies July 20, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Richard Gross & Hawthorne Study - Gross Hawthorne, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Richard D. Gross Letters (on Hawthorne) August 29, 1979 Letter (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - R. D. Gross Report on Hawthorne (copy of original) 1931 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Homer Hibarger Data 11/29/76, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hibarger Data, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Collection of Correspondence with Homer Hibarger on Hawthorne 1957, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Addresses of Dickson & Hibarger (1932) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Bibliography of Hawthorne Progress Report - pp. 134 Spaeth, Shepard, & Vernon all listed 11-21-91, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Corrected Bibliography from Progress Report # 1 by Hibarger 1927 - Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Pages 343-345 of Thesis & Bibliography of Hibarger Report (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Nelson J. Hunt, "The Hawthorne Studies" (Mgt. 401, Spring, 1963) May 1963 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Photocopy of Letter, Hibarger 1956 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Copy of original (partial)
  - Death Certificate of Obie Hunt from Relay Test Room 7/2/42 - Born 1903 - (April 4, 1903) - 39 years old - Hawthorne, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Michael Hunt Data and Hawthorne, 1956-1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Michael Hunt Letter 2/8/65 on Obie Hunt (From Chipman), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Data on Obie Hunt and Hawthorne, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Hawthorne Data - Bob Laskowski, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Robert Laskowski 1972 Investigation into Hawthorne Studies (letters) (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Turner, Dr. Claire E., 1933-1971 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Envelope and original article
  - Lang, Richard E., 1924-1940 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Western Electric Library, 1923-1936 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence With Various Individuals on Hawthorne, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Original Guide to Relay Test Room Documents Hawthorne, 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Items to Locate on Trip to Hawthorne 11-15-79, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Data on Files at West Street, NYC on Telephone Co. - 10-19-64 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Sept 23, 1964 Letter From A.G. Benedix on Hibarger & Hunt (Box 4, Folder 52)
    Original Letter
  - Correspondence with F. Harbison (Director) on Hawthorne, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with Marshall Dimock - NYU on Hawthorne Experiments 9/15/58, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Survey to Find Old Hawthorne People 1964 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Search for Associates of Mayo & Hawthorne People Involved in Tests (Robert Laskoski - 1972) (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Copies of Letter with George F. Lombard on Mayo 11/4/57 - Original Letter in File of Original Data 8/7/96, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Osgood Lovekin, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Osgood Lovekin 1964 on Hawthorne, 1964 Letter (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Osgood Lovekin Letter to General Electric 5/7/1929 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence with Bob Lovett of Harvard, 1961-1978 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Robert Lovett Letter of 11/25/58, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Robert Lovett Letter 12/1/76 (on Taylor Bust, Donham, Barth), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - 1964-1978 Letters with Robert Lovett of Harvard Business School on Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 64)
    Copies and original documents
  - Robert Lovett, 1958-1977 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    Original documents and envelope
  - Robert Lovett 1978 Letters (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Florence Bartoshesky Letter Oct. 1979 Harvard Baker Library (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Bob Lovett Letters 1977 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Bob Lovett Letters 1979 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Letter with Bob Lovett (Harvard) 1959, from Lenard Lindsell - 1966, 1959-1966 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Robert Lovett to C.D. Wrege on George W. Peckham (Munsterberg Student) Oct. 5, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Letter to Lovett 11/21/58, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence with Robert Lovett 1979, 1958-1979 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Famous Firsts Article, Hawthorne, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Supplement to C.D. Wrege Report on Hawthorne Illumination Tests (1957, 9 pages, typed) (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Bibliography of Progress Report 1928 - pp. 134-135 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Documents in Relay Assembly Test Room - Hawthorne Files, 1927-1932 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Page 2 of 8/14/64 Letter to D.A. Moore on Hawthorne, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Johnson O'Connor (Connected to Hawthorne Studies), 1931-1973 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Letter From Marcus L. Ogden (W.E.) on Hawthorne Records 2/3/66, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Data on Coil Winding Speeds by John Oliva July 31, 1979 Original (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Calculating Piecework in Test Room - John Oliva Letter 2/28/82, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 8 Page Letter to John Oliva 8-2-79 on Incentives at Hawthorne, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Letter to John Oliva on Test Room Incentives 2/27/82, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Letter to Mrs. Oliver from C.D. Wrege, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Emily Osborne Letters Filed at Harvard (Osborne Search) Jan. 28, 1933, 3/17/30, 3/26/31, April 11, 1944, 1926-1964 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - List of Data in Mayo Files at Harvard School of Business Archives (2 pp.) From Lovett, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence on Emily Osborne and Hawthorne, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Emily Osborne Data & Hawthorne, 1930-1965 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - G.A. Pennock 1929 - Test Studies in Ind. Research at Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Copy of George A. Pennock Patent 1, 690, 457 - 11/6/28 on Apparatus for Pressing Operation, 1923-1928 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Robert R. Laskoski 1972 Letter in Searching for Hawthorne Studies Records File under George A. Pennock (Box 4, Folder 92)
    Envelope and original documents
  - George A. Pennock, "Test Studies in Industrial Research at Hawthorne", 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    Copies of original document and transparency
  - E. Mayo to G.A. Pennock December 7, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Mayo and Pennock Papers, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Mayo - Pennock Letters 11/27/28 Hawthorne, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Correspondence with D.A. Moore (Hawthorne Works, W.E.) 1964 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Mark Putnam Talk on Hawthorne on RATR 1929 (Thermo fax, 3 pages, #8, #9, #10, From Harvard Files) (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Correspondence with Mark Putnam on Hawthorne, Putnam Letters 1957 (Putnam), 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence with Theodore K. Quinn on Hawthorne & G.E. 1/9/59 & 9/30/58, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Fritz Roethlisberger Will Feb. 12, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Data on Death of Fritz Roethlisberger 5/17/74 From Western Electric News Brief June 3, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - On Death of Fritz Roethlisberger May 17, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Letter from Lenard Lindsell - 2/17/69 (On Western Electric & Hawthorne Studies), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Imogene Elgytha Rousseau (issued report on Test Room 1932), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - I. Rousseau's Impression of the Test Room July 7, 1932 (Hawthorne Microfiche 58 A1-A9) (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Ednah Blanchard - 10/7/1957 on C.E. Snow, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Blank Sheet MIT Paper (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Data on Death of C.E. Snow (11/11/62), MIT Letters on Snow 1977, 1923-1977 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - 1927 Snow Article - Tech Engineering News (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence with Ken Trofatter on Snow's Charts, Hawthorne, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - First Notes on Reading Snow's 1927 Article in Tech Engineering News at NY Public Library (File NYPL-VDAT-call letters), 1927- 1964 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - "In Memoriam" Charles E. Snow, Died Nov. 11, 1962 - Hawthorne Charles E. Snow (Box 4, Folder 113)
    Paper with cut outs of original article
  - Original Copy of Snow's 1927 Article in Tech Engineering News (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Temp and Humidity in Hawthorne Illumination Tests 1926- 1927 - Snow Records (Box 4, Folder 115)
    Copy of originals
  - Log Pages from C.E. Snow 1925 (also on Microfiche Reel) (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Hawthorne Microphone Nov. 21, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Charles E. Snow Data, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Letter to T.K. Stevenson of Western Electric on Hawthorne - June 10, 1958 - T.K. Stevenson Hawthorne 1958 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Data on Clarence Stoll of Western Electric - August 1926 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Western Electric Presents - Dubois (Press 1919-1926) Died 12/23/40, Bloom (Press 1926-1939) Died 8/14/53, Stoll (Press 1940-1947) Died 1/11/67, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Tests of National Research Council List Prepared For Clarence Stoll 1957, C.D. Wrege (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Negative Photostat of Letter from Clarence G. Stoll to C.D. Wrege, September 3, 1957 and Stoll Correspondence - Stoll (also Albright Data) (Box 4, Folder 123)
    Photostat, copies of originals and original documents
  - Data on Clarence G. Stoll from Western Electric News, July 1926-p. 4, Nov. 1926-p. 22-23, Aug. 1926-p.18 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Interview with Marie Sula May 2, 1933, Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Correspondence with Ruth Stone on Hawthorne 1964 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - 1957 & 1958 Letter from Clair Turner on Relay Test Room (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Clair Turner 1969 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Data on A.H. Ryan - Pulse Product 1918 (use for Test Room), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Tech Engineering News Drisko and Turner 1921-1934 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - George G. Morrell (MIT - died May 10, 1937) Assisted Clair Turner in Test Room Analysis - Hawthorne, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - C.E. Turner "I Remember" 1974 (Data on Test Room), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Data on Death of Clair Turner 11-27-74, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - MIT Data on Hawthorne (from Harvard Files) Turner Letter, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Viteles - 1958 Talk (Published 1959) Good for Hawthorne and "Cultism" in Research, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Ind - Worker Whitehead (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Pages of History Ind. Worker, M & W, 1924-1965 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Correspondence with Harriet Whitehead - 1986 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - T.N. Whitehead Data - Hawthorne, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Whitehead Proper Report on Relay Test Room 1933 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Thomas North Whitehead Death 11/23/69, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Alice M. Sapienza Correspondence 1982 (on Thomas N. Whitehead, She Worked with Paul Lawrence at Harvard in 1982) - Hawthorne, Whitehead, Mayo 1982 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Viteles on Hawthorne 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - T.N. Whitehead, Statistical Studies in Industrial Research: Second Progress Report 1934 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Photo static Copies of Pages from T.N. Whitehead's Industrial Worker Vol. I (on RATR) - Set #2, 1928-1982 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Whitehead (1938) on Payment in Test Room (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Mrs. Thomas N. Whitehead Correspondence on Industrial Worker 8/28/79, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Whitehead 1934 on Test Room (Harvard Business Review 1933, 1934) (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - T.N. Whitehead, Industrial Worker (1936) - Analysis of Relations Among RATR Operators (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Fred Wickert - Hawthorne & Industrial Psychology, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Charting the Hawthorne Studies (Manuscript Pages), 1928-1981 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Record of Trip to Hawthorne Works of Western Electric to Look for Old Photos 11/15-11/16, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Marty Labno - Western Electric, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Line Screen Photos of Hawthorne for N-File (Box 4, Folder 154)
    Original photos
  - Discovering the Real Hawthorne 1981 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Transparencies for Mostly Labno at Hawthorne for Photos Taken, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    Copies and original documents, transparencies
  - Roethlisberger Letter to Wright, 9/11/30 - On Research and Roethlisberger's Trip to Hawthorne (4 pages), 1930 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - National Research Council - Committee on Work in Industry, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Data on Harold Wright (Joined W.E. 9/25/23 to 9/12/25, Then Returned 1/28/26 and Left 1/31/44) - Data For Mrs. Chambers at Hawthorne Personnel Dept. via Leonard Lindsell 8/25/64, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Henry Zeiger, MIT "The Industrial Lighting Situation" April 1924 - Use For Hawthorne (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Correspondence on Henry Zeiger Report and Melvin Weig at Edison Site 2/11/64, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 161)
- Western Electric Company Data, Mica Splitting, and Bank Wiring Observation Room. Background on Western Electric Co.; correspondence with some officers; data on products made etc., some information on Mica Splitting and Bank Wiring observation room stu (Box 5)
  - GMI Correspondence - 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Western Electric Plans for 50th Anniversary of Hawthorne Studies, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Data on Manufacturing Activities at W.E. (Definitions of "Works" and "Shops") From W.E. & The Bell System 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Organization of Western Electric 1927 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Western Electric 1922 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Data on Western Electric from Industrial Engineer, Jan 1924, Vol. 82, #1, p. 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - B41 B43 Relays, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Original documents in folder
  - American Management Association, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Data from Engineering and Science in the Bell System Book on Relays and Coils, 1924-1926 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "History of Western Electric," Western Electric News April 1912, Vol. 1, No. 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Survey of Hawthorne Microphone - For Hawthorne Research, 1922-1925 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Robert G. Lewis AT&T Archives 195 Broadway - AT&T 1984 Archives (Room 01-537, NY 10007/212-393-4723) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hawthorne Works and The Personnel Job, 1922-1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    2 original booklets
  - Western Electric Protection Control by Clarence G. Stoll - Published in Mgt. Industries, Jan. 1927, Feb. 1927 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with Robert Boardman on Article on Relay Assembly Test Room in WE March/April 1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Laskoski Correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Data on Western Electric "Bogey", 1925-1928 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Memo from F.J. Cihlar to: T. Mountain, J.H. Bolt, and V.L. Schad on "New Hawthorne" 11/15/79, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "Hawthorne 75" WE. March-April 1978 (75th Anniversary) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Wage Incentives at Hawthorne 1925, William Hosford of WE, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Copy of Original
  - Baudot Code used for 5 unit punched tape like tape used in recorder in Relay Test Room at Hawthorne (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Copy of original (laminated)
  - Copy from Western Electric Hawthorne Works File, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Diagrams of Test Locations at Hawthorne 3-3-80, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 1922 Data on Western Electric (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Western Electric Departmental Clients June 1922 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Melvin T. Copeland on Hawthorne and Mayo, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Letter to Walter Dietz, 78 Mountain Ave, Summit, NJ 9/15/57 - Deitz-Hawthorne 1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 1964 Request to Print Papers from MCW - Briggs Harvard Univ. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Sources on Hawthorne Studies C.D. Wrege 1959 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Decisions at Hawthorne Paper 1983 Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Who Were Mayo's "Many Hands" ? Wrege Paper 1981 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Discovering Hawthorne's "Roots" - Parsons, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Preface to Dissertation and Extra Pages (Original), 1961 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Pages on Carey & Hawthorne - For Article on "Carey The Critic" 8/31/79, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Notes for New Light on Hawthorne (Purposed CD Wrege Book 1964) (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 4 Page Summary of Symposium on" Hawthorne: Getting the Story Straight" 1982 Academy of Management (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Abstract of Dissertation on Hawthorne, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Hawthorne's "Roots": Search for Original Records, C.D. Wrege (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Notes on "Solving Mayo's Mystery" Paper - January 13, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Misc. Papers from New Light on Hawthorne 1971 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Abbreviations for New Light on Hawthorne Book - 1964, 3 pages (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Discovering the Real Hawthorne, Wrege Paper 1980 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Who Were Elton Mayo's Many Hands? 1981, Wrege Paper, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Letters for Hawthorne Articles 1971 By Synectics Class (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Discovery of the Real Hawthorne, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Transparencies, Relay Test Rooms, 1928-1932 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Transparencies of originals